it's depressing that if it continues like this
удручает что если так будет продолжаться
in terms of the fact that, well, even that
в плане того что ну условно даже та
mortgage rate That's how it
ставка по ипотеке Вот как сейчас
turned out now Well, that is, there's inflation and all
получилась Ну то есть там инфляция всё
that with you The key rate is 21, which
такое у вас Ключевая ставка 21 это
means the mortgage is even higher, yes, that is, it
значит ипотека ещё выше да то есть
turns out that it has become unrealistic to
получается ээ ипотеку стало нереально
take out a mortgage now Well, an apartment of 12 million in Moscow,
брать теперь Ну квартира 12 млн в Москве
70 million
70 млн
overpayment Hello I'm already scared to
переплата Здравствуйте Мне уже страшно
say something, it's scary, yes, it's
говорить что-то страшно да
okay, learn to be brave I'm from Ukraine, the
нормально учись быть смелым Я из Украины
city of Khmelnitsky, where are you
город Хмельницкий Ты
from I'm from Russia, the city of Tyumen How
откуда Я из России город Тюмень Сколько
old are you,
лет тебе
20, let's say
20 давай
twenty years old Yes, it's so
двадцатилетнего Да мне на стуле так
comfortable for me to just
удобно просто
sit on a chair What are we talking about What are you
сидеть О чём обща
studying to be
На кого учишься
I'm a humanities
я я гуманитарный
student Translation studies Translation
Нау переводоведение
studies What is
переводоведение Что такое
translation studies Well, it's a faculty Well, I don't
переводоведение Ну это факультет Ну не
want to say Where are you studying, I wonder, well,
хочу говорить Где учишься интересно ну
tell me, well, no Yes, not where are you studying, but the
скажи ну не Да не где учишься а
specialty Well, I don't want to, so say the
специальность Ну не хочу так скажи
specialty, not me I don't
специальность не мне Она сама не
like it myself, that I'm afraid Okay, okay, I
нравится что боюсь Ладно ладно на
study on advertising, in short, on advertising I
рекламе учусь короче на рекламе
understand What is the main principle of
Понял Какой главный принцип
advertising the main principle of advertising is
рекламы главный принцип
information content or what are you talking about
информативность или вы про что вы Про
What are you talking about  in the first year they tell you
что говорите на первом курсе вам говорят
three principles of advertising of which there is the
три принципа рекламы из них есть
main one Come on you are not
главный Да ладно ты не на рекламе
studying advertising I graduated from the faculty of
учишься Я рекламу заканчивал факультет
advertising department you are clearly not
кафедру рекламы ты явно не на рекламе
studying advertising then who are you studying No well seriously
учишься то на кого ты учишься Не ну
I am not joking
реально говорю я не
Listen Why did Russia attack
пошутил Слушай Почему Россия напала на
Ukraine Tell me
Украину Расскажи мне
advertiser I don't know advertising
рекламщик не знаю
Oh now it's night for me already need to get
рекла Ой сейчас у меня ночь уже надо
ready my mys what will I
собраться мыс что я там в интернете
end up on the Internet after such words Well if you are
окажусь после таких слов Ну если
interested let's talk you will find out
интересно поговорим окажешься
where to look for the channel you can immediately yes
что где канал искать можно сразу да
Let's talk normally first then you
Давай нормально поговорим сначала потом
will be about the channel you are dragging it out for so long
те будешь про канал ты так долго тянешь
I
я
switch Yes what attacked I don't know it happened It
переключись Да что напало не знаю вышло
probably happened that well how did it
Так получилось наверное что ну как
happen well somehow it happened I don't know at all
вышло ну как-то так вышло я вообще не
if you
знаю если честно
explain honestly Well well
объясни Ну
protection of the country's sovereignty Probably
ну защита суверенитета страны Наверно
so if in general this is how it is in the World Cup protection of the
так если в общем так в ЧМ защита
country's sovereignty Well don't let NATO near the border
страны Ну не подпускать НАТО к границе
like What NATO Well for now None Well
типа Какое НАТО Ну пока Да никакое Ну
basically already on the news today
уже в принципе сегодня по новостям уже
None in principle Unfortunately or
Никакое в принципе К сожалению или к
fortunately I
счастью
know I can't understand your position What
зна Я не могу понять твою позицию Какое
NATO because of what Russia attacked  Ukraine
НАТО из-за чего Россия напала на Украину
and some regions were written into the
и часть областей взяла вписала себе в
constitution
конституцию
Well, at
Ну как
least Well, there are no minerals there,
минимум Ну не полезных ископаемых там
I don’t know, like, what did I write in, in
нет я не знаю типа что что вписала на
fact, I don’t know, like, what did I write in. Like, what is the
самом деле не знаю что вписала
point of joining, I don’t
Типа какой типа смысл присоединения не
know, to be honest, I won’t
знаю если честно не
answer, if you say so, you
отвечу если так говорить
think Well, it’s already difficult to resist,
считаешь Ну тут уже сложно противиться
here I’m already just, well, like, he’s already
ту тут я уже просто ну как бы он он уже
just here, you see What’s the point, like, whose
просто тут видите В чём смысл типа чей
not Whose has it been
не Чей он уже столько лет как бы за
enshrined in the Constitution for so many years, like, not The Constitution,
закреплён Конституцией не Конституция
like, he’s already objectively, like, Russian
типа он уже объективно типа российский
What does objectively mean
Что значит объективно
Well,
Ну
damn, how many years have passed since
прошло блин сколько с четырнадцатого
1914, it turns out, she Well, 11 years, and
года получается ше Ну так 11 лет А как
how do you imagine, like,
Как вы себе представляете типа там там
roughly speaking, it has grown Well, that is, this Here’s an
грубо говоря выросло Ну то есть
example Yes, an example is Nagorno-
это Вот пример Да пример Нагорный
Karabakh Yes, how many years have passed since
Карабах Да сколько с восемьдесят там
1988 or 1989, Azerbaijan has
восьмого или восемьдесят девятого году
n’t been in Azerbaijan, so
года не был в Азербайджане вот с пришёл
Azerbaijan came, and what’s the problem anyway
Азербайджан и что в чём вообще проблема
I don’t understand Look, Russia came in
Я не понимаю смотри Россия пришла в
1914 Yes, it didn’t bother it that
четырнадцатом году да её не смущало что
Crimea had been Ukrainian for so many years, though for
Крым был украинский столько лет правда
more than half a century.
более полувека
what's the problem that he's been here in
то в чём проблема то что он пробыл тут в
Russia for some 11
России каких-то 11
years, you can hear me now, yes, I say,
лет слышно меня вот теперь да говорю
if Russia came and took Crimea And I didn't
если Россия пришла и забрала Крым И не
give a damn Well, like, what's the matter with him being objectively
парилась Ну типа там что он объективно
Ukrainian, that he's been in Ukraine for more than 50 years,
украинский что там больше 50 лет он в
yeah, yeah, what's the problem that
Украине да Ага То в чём проблема что там
people have lived in Russia for 11 years, well, they'll tell
11 лет люди пожили в России ну скажут
those who came from Russia to Crimea, they'll tell you
тем кто приехал из России в Крым скажут
You have 24 hours with a noose,
У вас есть 24 часа с петля
not a trial,
не упе того
and the rest are very simple, yeah, those who
проб а остальные очень просто да Кто
collaborated with the regime, the military, the police,
сотрудничал с режимом военные полиция
who were there, they'll run away themselves even before
которые были да сами убегут ещ до
Ukraine came, the rest, if you were a teacher at
Украины остальные если ты был учитель в
school or a salesperson in a store, you
школе или там продавец в магазине как
worked and will continue to work,
проработал так и будешь работать
Ukrainian will get it, I know why it was annexed,
украинский знаю зачем он присоединён
access to the sea, the Black Sea, why, that is,
выход к морю Чёрное море зачем а то есть
without this, stop, access to the Black Sea Yes,
без этого стоп выход к чёрному морю Да
when Crimea was annexed, Russia had access to the
когда присоединили Крым у России был
Black Sea, Krasnodar Krai, but there was
выход в Чёрном море Краснодарский край а
no access to Crimea,
выхода к Крыму не
look, let's do it, Russia had access
было смотри давай так у России был выход
to the Black Sea until
в р к чёрному морю до четырнадцатого
2014, well, there was an expansion, that is,
года ну произошло же расширение То есть
it's more or less  what Well more Well how there are
это более более что Ну более Ну как
more exits, roughly speaking, there are no
выходов стало больше грубо говоря на
exits for the whole island, look, uh,
целый остров нет выходов нет смотри ээ
in order for there to be an exit from Crimea, there needs to be an
для того чтобы был выход из Крыма нужно
entrance to Crimea Well, there was no entrance to Crimea The Crimean Bridge was
Ну входа в Крым не было Крымский мост
built, so look, from
построили было так это смотри из
Novorossiysk from there Yes, in fact, from
Новороссийска оттуда Да по сути из
Krasnodar, where there is an exit to the sea, you need to
Краснодара где есть выход в море нужно
go to Crimea in order to go out to sea from there,
ехать в Крым чтобы оттуда выйти в море
something is wrong Is it true here
что-то не так Правда тут
Well no, why is here Krasnodar Krai
Ну нет почему вот вот Краснодарский край
and here it is, Queen, that is, we have
и вот он Квин то есть мы
shifted Krasnodar Krai, the exit to the
сместились Краснодарский край выход в
sea was from Krasnodar Krai, there is the port of
море был с Краснодарского края там порт
Novorossiya, Tops Anapa, there is blah-blah-blah Yes,
новороссии топс Анапа там бла-бла-бла Да
why instead of going out to sea in
зачем вместо того чтобы выйти в море в
Novorossiysk Why go around via the
Новороссийске Зачем объезжать через
Crimean Bridge to Crimea and go out
Крымский мост в Крым и выходить в Крыму
to sea in Crimea, what's the joke? It's more
в море в чём прикол Это же
expensive, why do you need to run Crimea from the
дороже почему зачем вам бежать Крым же с
edge But why go across the Crimean Bridge to
края Но зачем ехать по крымскому мосту в
Crimea if from Krasnodar Krai if you
Крым если из Краснодарского края если
can go out to sea directly from Krasnodar
можно в море выйти сразу из
Krai Well Well, that's how it is,
края
it sounds strange in general,
Ну Ну так это так это в целом странно
in the sense of why, like, the exit has become
звучит в смысле зачем ну типа выход стал
closer in this creature, shorten it further,
ближе в этом существо сократи дальше
yes, how  Look again if you
стал да как ещё раз смотри если ты из
went from Rostov to Crimea Oh, you went to the
Ростова выходил в Крым Ой выходил на
sea You went through Krasnodar Krai,
море Ты выходил через Краснодарский край
in order to go from Rostov to the sea
тебе чтобы из Ростова выйти ээ в море
through Crimea, you have to go to Crimea,
через Крым тебе аж надо проехать в Крым
so in this USA, now there is a port in Crimea,
так в этом США что теперь в Крыму есть
now you can go from Crimea to the
порт теперь можно из Крыма выходить в
Black Sea Why go out again, who needs to
Чёрное море Зачем выхо ещё раз кому
go out, if someone, look again, who is
выходить если кто-то смотри ещё раз тот
some kind of entrepreneur in Russia
кто вот в России какой-то
Yes, he wants to export grain, he needs to
предприниматель Да хочет вывезти зерно
bring it to the sea Previously, he
ему нужно до моря его довести Раньше он
brought it to Krasnodar Krai and carried it But
доводил до Краснодарского края и Вёз А
now he needs to go all the way to
теперь ему нужно заехать аж в
Crimea, how has it become better then, I do
Крым в чём тогда лучше стало
n’t understand the question How has it become worse, that’s the
я я не понимаю вопрос В чём хуже стало
question Well, look again, I
вот в чём вопрос Ну смотри ещё раз я
just don’t understand, there was access to the sea,
просто не понимаю был выход к морю
close to all the logistics, and Crimea was
близкий да ко всей логистике а Крым
seized What’s the question in general Well,
захватили В чём вообще в целом-то вопрос
you said that Crimea was seized so that there would be
Ну ты же сказал что Крым захватили чтобы
access to the sea Well,
был выход к
and they held a referendum In general, it
морю Ну и провели референдум В общем
wasn’t like that either, it’s like Why Well,
тоже было не так это типа вот Для чего
access to the sea Well, there
Ну выход к морю
was access to the sea, but now because of the war Yes,
был а сейчас сейчас из-за войны Да
now Russia has no access to  sea ​​in
теперь у России нету выхода к морю в
Crimea because the entire fleet fled
Крыму потому что весь флот Убежал
from there because of the Ukrainian these
оттуда из-за украинских этих
Novorossiysk about the fact that the unmanned boats
новоросси про то что без экипажный лодок
This was when When the Crimean
Это же было это когда Когда Крымский
Bridge was attacked when the pos smy I mean you
мост атаковали когда пос смы В смысле ты
news not this has become so mundane
новости не это стало настолько будничный
Yes already about these unmanned boats they are
Да уже про эти без экипажный катеры их
already making them with machine guns even yes he is driving a
уже делают с пулемётами даже да он едет
boat Three boats are driving Yes one uh with
катер Едут три катера Да один ээ с
machine guns shoots down these Uh how they shoot
пулемётов сбивает эти Ээ как они палят
at helicopters so that helicopters do not
по вертолёта чтобы вертолёты не
work on boats there now is already
отрабатывали по катерам там сейчас уже
generally an anecdote so the Russian fleet has already
вообще анекдот так Российский флот уже
fled from Novorossiysk already part is in the
убежал с Новороссийска уже стоит часть в
bay Novorossiysk part fled there they
бухте Новороссийская часть убежала туда
want to build in Abkhazia in
хотят аж в Абхазии строить в
Ochamchire all the fleet is gone Russian fleet is
очамчире всё флота нет Российский флот
completely excluded from the game But look at you as an
полностью А вот тебе смотри тебе как
ordinary citizen yes the Russian
простому гражданину да Российской
Federation has become better or worse from the
Федерации лучше или хуже стало от
seizure of
захвата
Crimea I don't know Well in the summer it is probably
Крыма не знаю Ну летом там наверное
great to relax there and there was no I'm just
классно отдыхать а не было Просто я
asking you have become better or worse from the
спрашиваю тебе стало лучше или хуже от
seizure of Crimea
захвата Крыма
Well it hasn't become worse better I don't know I haven't been
Ну хуже не стало лучше не знаю не был
there  I can't say Well, like for myself, what are the
там не могу сказать ти Ну типа для себя
advantages? What do I feel? If I'm a simple
плюсы я Какие ощути я если я простой
person, well, yes, for ordinary people,
человек так вот да для простых людей
life has become better since the seizure of Crimea or
лучше стало жить от захвата Крыма или
not Well, I don't know, if it's just by the
нет Ну не знаю если типа просто по
deductive method to go there conditionally Well,
дедуктивно методу идти там условно Ну
there you got tourism
там же ты получил получается туризм
tourism analogs to the treasury Well, like, I don't know,
туризм аналоги в казну Ну типа не знаю
probably, that's the
наверно тако такого
point, you just need to
смысла надо в этом надо просто всм
understand everything very well in terms of the whole
разбираться очень сильно в плане во всей
situation of the conflict In order to understand, it became
ситуации конфликта Чтобы понимать стало
better, not better, I said by the way such a
лучше не лучше я ты сказал кстати такую
phrase, the deductive method And what is the
фразу дедуктивный метод А что такое
deductive
дедуктивный
method What is
метод Что
there from the opposite to the one Yes, and there is no
там от обратного к единому Да
single inductive deductive There is
так и ес единого индуктивный дедуктивный
induction and deduction Yes, what
есть вот индукция и дедукция Да что
is deduction,
такое дедукция
topchek
топчек
private or vice versa Well,
частны или наоборот
you said the deductive method I'm just
Ну ты сказал дедуктивный методом Просто
wondering I don't use this
мне интересно Я не использую такое это
Sherlock Holmes liked to say this Well, yes,
Шерлок Холмс любил такое говорить Ну да
but I say It seems from the general to the particular Well,
но я и говорю Вроде от общего к частному
when
Ну когда
we don't know the answer, we try to pick up not
мы не знаю ответ пытаемся подобрать не
from the general to the particular - This is
от общего к частному - Это
differentiation from the particular to the general -
дифференцирование от частного к общему -
this is
это
integration And what is mathematics
интегрирование А что такое математико
bad I honestly haven't yet  mathematician got it then
плохо Я честно ещ не математик понял
look Let's do it this way and from the fact that Russia
то смотри Давай так а от того что Россия
started a full-scale war against
начала полномасштабную войну против
Ukraine Yes, your life has changed for the
Украины Да твоя жизнь изменилась к
better or for the
лучшему или к
worse
хуже
Well, something in it has definitely changed Yes, in
Ну что-то в ней определённо изменилось
any case, so that well Well,
Да по-любому так
it doesn't bother me much but the
Ну то меня это не парит сильно но уход
company's departure there and all that Well, that is, it
компании там вот это всё Ну то есть это
was e well, like, it's clear that anyone will
было е ну типа то что понятно что любой
say I don't know well,
скажет я не знаю
like, I do
ну как
n't know maybe it's become more difficult to
бы не знаю может Шенген стало сложнее
get a Schengen visa in some senses Well, where they won't let you
получить в некоторых смыслах Ну куда там
in Poland they won't let you in Well, it seems like
не пустят в Польшу не пустят
you never went anywhere before
Ну так ты походу и раньше никуда не
and you don't go anywhere now
ездил и сейчас никуда не ездишь
Well, probably the fact that well, did
Ну наверное
you start living better or
то что что ну ты стал лучше жить или
worse from the war against
хуже от войны против
Ukraine in this with
Украины в этом с
what is so average, no better, no worse How is it
что так средне наве не лучше не хуже Как
better at all it hasn't changed just like in a
лучше вообще не изменилось просто как на
cemetery, decay and despondency
кладбище тлен такой и уныние
yes yes no on Well, like, like, on the
да да нет на Ну как ну
planet of the fact that well, conditionally, even that
типа плане того что ну условно даже та
mortgage rate That's how it
ставка по ипотеке Вот как сейчас
turned out now Well, that is, there's inflation and all that Well,
получилась Ну то есть там инфляция всё
of course That is, it's felt
такое Ну конечно То есть это чувствуется
in any case Like if I just
в любом случае Типа если ято я просто
like I won't take it from you I'm telling you how it
типа Я же вам брать не буду я говорю как
is just like not because it's bad but
есть просто типа не потому что плохо но
like yes I'm not against the fact that
типа есть я как против факта не попр то
you already have 21 your key rate is 21
у вас уже 21 у вас Ключевая ставка 21
this means the mortgage is even higher yes that is it
это значит ипотека ещё выше да то есть
turns out that it has become unrealistic to
получается ээ ипотеку стало нереально
take out a mortgage now Well an apartment is 12 million in Moscow
брать теперь Ну квартира 12 млн в Москве
70 million overpayment let's do it 12 million is
70 млн переплата давай так 12 млн - это
120,000 rubles oh 120,000 dollars and 70
120.000 рублей ой 120.000 долларов а 70
million is 700,000 dollars well yes that is to
млн - это 700.000 долларов ну да то есть
take an apartment in Moscow on a mortgage
чтобы взять квартиру в Москве в ипотеку
Yes for 120,000 dollars you still need to
Да за за 120.000 долларов Нужно ещё
overpay 700,000 dollars well in short for a
переплатить 700.000 долларов ну короче
million
за миллион
dollars well yes in short
долларов ну да короче
Wait are you seriously
Подожди это ты на полном серьёзе сейчас
saying this right now yes Well damn what didn't I get it I got it yes Well come on I'll
говоришь да Ну блин что не я понял Понял
go straight to the mortgage calculator
да А ну даре калькулятор ипотеки зайду
no mortgage calculator I got it
вот пря нет калькулятор ипотеки я понял
Yes I mean what is
Да я имею в виду что
there or are you in general talking about the fact that it is like that Oh well
там или вы в целом про то что так есть О
like well yes that's how it is what can I
ну типа ну да вот так есть что я могу
say for those
сказать для тех
who lived and then decided to buy an
кто жил и потом решил купить себе
apartment for themselves yes of course it was a bummer
квартиру да [__] произошёл конечно
million bucks for an apartment in
лям баксов за квартиру в
Moscow and this is such a modest
Москве а это такой как бы не скромный
question And what kind of apartment and not I don’t know
вопрос А какая э квартира а не я не знаю
it was just a quick example I understood It’s
это просто был быстрый пример понял Это
like how many rooms are there I won’t
типа какая там сколько комнат это не
say anything like that I don’t
скажу ничего типа таких такой не
have information like that Well in short in general
располагаю информацие Ну короче в общем
no well the prospect of life Of course it’s
не ну перспектива жизни Конечно
cool to save up a million bucks and
прикольная накопить миллион баксов и
buy an apartment in Moscow
купить квартиру в Москве
gradually not Well then Well I don’t know then
постепенно не Ну потом Ну не знаю потом
it will become better probably in any case it wo
это лучше станет наверно в любом случае
n’t continue like this all my
так не будет продолжаться всю
life Well what are you saying well it won’t be
жизнь Ну что вы вы ну не
Well in any case no I think
будет будет Ну в любом случае не я думаю
I think that for a million bucks you can Well
я думаю что за миллион баксов можно Ну
somehow an island in Greece to buy
как-то остров се в Греции купить
not a mortgage
не ипотеку
people I don’t know either who know their life
люди не знаю либо которы свою жизнь знаю
or who are ready for
либо которые готовы к банкротству
subsequent bankruptcy this I don’t
последующему это я не
know bankrupt Yes you will fall out bankrupt half of the mortgage
знаю банкрот Да ты половину ипотеки
Well the mortgage
выпаде банкротом Ну ипотека
will be taken away not this if you have The
заберётся не это если у тебя
only thing that is the only housing I
Единственное что единственное жильё
say by law I don’t take away that is not
говорю по закону Не забираю то есть не
so if you have a mortgage right here like What
так если у тебя ипотечная тут же как Что
is a mortgage a mortgage is when you
такое ипотека ипотека - это когда ты
take out a loan secured by this
берёшь кредит под залог вот этого
property it’s not so clear I understand I
имущества не так понятно я я понимаю Я
mean that under  the law can't take it
имею виду что под закон не могут её
away That's what I mean they can't Well they
забрать Вот чем В смысле не могут могут
write off I write off the loan and that's it And those are oh
Ну списывают я списывают кредит и всё И
yeah and you suffer from the fact that you're bankrupt
а да и ты страдаешь тем что ты банкрот
so Listen if it were like that then
так бы Слушай если бы так было
10 million cunning Russians would take out a loan
то 10 млн хитро россиян брали бы кредит
for a [ __ ] apartment and immediately declare
на офигенную хату и сразу бы объявляли
themselves
себ о
bankrupt True Well
банкротом Правда Ну от этого же тоже
there are also sanctions from this what
свои санкции есть какие
sanctions or am I getting confused in general [ __ ] when
санкции или я путаю вообще [__] когда
can I generally rock probably yes
там может я вообще скал наверное да у
I have a feeling that in
меня такое ощущение что
general bud understood And by the way do you have friends
вобще буд понял А у тебя кстати знакомые
who died in the
есть которые погибли на
war No
войне Не
but the
а
wounded well I
раненые ну раненых
know the wounded how they got to the
знаю как они попали на
war
войну
well by mobilization which we had
ну по мобилизации которая была у нас
then the first like itself And what They were taken
тогда первая типа сама А что Их забрали
Well like from the factory they took from
Ну типа с завода забрали
where Well not from the factory But like yes they
откуда Ну не с завода Но типа да пришли
just came and said like that like yeah Well
просто сказали типа что вот типа да Ну
during mobilization during that That is when like there
при мобилизации при той То есть когда
was a set then yes there was lo I
типа был набор тогда да было ло такое
understood And how did they die not wounded like didn't
понял А как они погибли не ранин типа не
die oh they were wounded like how did they get
погиб ой ранили типа как им попало
somewhere there well a splinter Yes it flew like
куда-то там ну осколок Да прилетел вроде
in the arm or where was that yeah Well yes yes it
в руку или куда было такое да Ну
was And how much did they
да то да было И сколько
pay
выплатили
Well how much  there I don't remember the exact number, well, it's
Ну сколько там что-то точную цифру не
normal, but in short I don't
помню ну типа ну нормально но так короче
know, there's just a basically
не знаю там там просто в принципе
restorable wound, that is, it's not that nothing was
восстанавливаемая рана то есть там не то
torn off, nothing terrible like
что не оторвало ничего е страшного
that, that is, it's normal, in short,
такого не было То есть нормально Короче
for something like that, I kind of remember that it's
для такого пому что-то вроде помню что
normal, I have a friend from Rostov, too, his name
нормально У меня знакомый тоже из
was Mobil, Sanya Prokhorov, in
сам мобили звали его Саня Прохоров то
short, a
короче у него
drone flew
Дрон
in. They were driving a car. The drone flew in and pierced the
прилетел Они ехали на машине Дрон
windshield, in short, the
залетел прямо пробил лобовуху короче
two guys who were sitting in the front were completely destroyed, and
двум пацанам которые спереди сидел им
he was completely destroyed by
вообще а ему
shrapnel. Well, how did the shrapnel hit
осколками Ну короче как осколки попали
him during the operations,
ему в операциях
completely destroyed him. Yes, in
коче полностью Да
short, he says, even with a girl, it's
короче говорит даже с девкой типа
scary to meet, like, he
стрёмно познакомиться
gets up, yeah, well, no, well,
типа типа вроде встаёт да А ну типа нет
somehow he took it off, he says, yeah, well, I thought at least that way,
ну как-то он снял го говорит Да ну думал
like, She got scared and ran
хоть так типа Она испугалась
away, well, I even, Nelya, how does it look, to be
убежала ну я даже Неля как это выглядит
honest, Well, they cut it off, they sewed up that little
если честно Ну отрезали зашили там эту
machine there and that's it, just a stick, in short, without. Well, it's
машинку и всё просто палка короче без Ну
tough, yeah, what, yeah, I don't come here, like,
жёстко плохо да Что да я я сюда не
conditionally, like, I don't come here to
условно типа не захожу сюда кого-то по
insult someone, like,  something yes me too I
оскорблять типа что-то да я тоже я
just want to have a normal conversation that's the
только нормально поговорить пообщаться
whole point yes yes
это же в том-то и смысл есть это да да
like I don't And what do you think, here you have
типа я не А как Как ты считаешь вот у
people who live in Russia, do they
вас люди которые в России живут они в
mostly support this war
большинстве своём поддерживают эту войну
or don't
или не
support it Well, among the older population,
поддерживаю Ну среди старшего населени
probably more support it, among the
наверное больше поддерживают среди
youth, probably many don't
молодёжи наверное много кто не
support it Well I think so well that is to say,
поддерживает Ну думаю так ну то есть как
well, among the youth I just don't know I
бы ну среди молодёжи просто не знаю я
just understand about the older people yeah what Oh
просто про старших прям понятно да что О
probably yes And about the youth Well, after all,
наверно да А про молодёжь Ну всё-таки
like there are Well, in principle, even
типа есть Ну ну в принципе даже вот
when people are with you They say
рядом когда люди с тобой Они же говорят
That is, if about the university, conditionally,
То есть если о университете условно
there are those
есть кто
against it
против
Well, for someone there, conditionally, it was important
Ну для кого-то там условно же было важно
yes, for example, that there are brands there, all that sort of
да например что бренды там есть всё
thing, well I
вещи
understand And what do you think, where is the best
понял А как ты считаешь где лучший
standard of living in Russia or in
уровень жизни в России или в
Europe Well, damn, at
Европе Ну блин на
work, if we talk How do you
работах если говорим Как как
think that's a good
считаешь это хороший
question Well like Well, the middle class in Europe
вопрос Ну типа Ну средний класс в Европе
will definitely be higher than in Russia, that's
по-любому выше будет чем в России так
good And who lives better in Russia,
хорошо А кто в России лучше
but I'm sure that being rich in Russia is
живёт но я уверен что богатым в России
very cool, here you go, I won't name a
быть очень классно ро вот ти я не назову
country where it's easy to be rich in
такую страну где богатым быть просто в
Russia  rich I think Like if you have
России богатым я считаю Типа если у тебя
a lot of money in Russia You are the best country
в России много денег Ты лучшая страна
to live in Well it seems to me that if
чтобы жить Ну мне кажется что если у
you have a lot of money then America is not bad
тебя много денег то и в Америке неплохо
and the Emirates and
и в Эмиратах и в
Germany Well I'm just from the position that it's
Германии Ну я просто так из позиции что
good Here about interest Pony understand middle
хоро Вот про интерес Поня средний
class in Europe Yeah below middle class
ласс Европе Ага ниже среднего класса
worker it is better to live in Europe A rich man
рабочий это живёт лучше в Европе Богач
lives better in Russia can you explain
лучше живёт в России можешь объяснить
how a rich man in Russia lives better than a rich man in
чем богач в России живёт лучше богача во
France Well I just from which side I
Франции Ну я я просто с какой стороны
look like like uh uh well
смотрю типа вот ээ
individual entrepreneurship
э ну индивидуальное предпринимательство
Well here's how to earn money you need to
Ну вот как заработать нужно типа бизнес
do business again again Rich man let's do it
делать ещё раз ещё раз Богач давай так
Rich man worries about individual
Богач переживает про индивидуальное
entrepreneurship no No I mean
предпринимательство не Нет я имею в виду
from which side I look what you have
что я с какой стороны смотрю что у тебя
like conditionally there are not billions billions
типа условно там не миллиарды миллиарды
account but just You for example well Your
счёт а просто Ты например ну Твоя
salary conditionally we will Well roughly speaking
зарплата условно будем Ну грубо говоря
we will say that 300-400 thousand rubles Yes that's the
будем говорить что 300-400 000 руб Да
middle class Well no it's not the
вот так это средний класс Ну нет это не
middle class middle
средний клас средний
class Like you are on par with Europe That's no
класс Типа вы по Европе
longer the middle class Well
сравнялась Это уже не средний класс Ну
4,000 dollars are not rich Well no
4.000 долларов это не богачи
what are you saying well 4,000  dollars a
Ну ну нет вы что ну 4.000 долларов в
month is not rich What are you talking about it is not
месяц это не богач Вот вы что это не
middle class It's like No well or like in
средний класс Это как Не ну или типа по
Moscow if you look probably Wait
Москве если смотреть наверное Подожди
Stop Do I understand correctly that you are saying
Стоп Я правильно понимаю что ты говоришь
that 4,000 dollars a month in Russia is
что 4.000 долларов в месяц в России это
richer Well if he lives in the region Yeah
богаче Ну если он живёт в регионе Да
okay and the middle class is
хорошо а средний класс это
how much 150 Well up to 200 I understand that is the
сколько 150 Ну до 200 понял то есть
middle class In Russia it is 15-200
средний класс В России - это 15-200
dollars 4,000 dollars is
долларов 4.000 долларов - это
Rich Well already relatively 4,000 dollars Is this
Богач Ну уже относительно 4.000 долларов
normal in Russia then it is normal
Это в России это нормально то нормально
or are you
или это ты
Rich Well I don't know go it is definitely above the middle
Богач Ну я не знаю го это выше среднего
class but not rich And how How do you
класса точно но не богач А как Как ты
think what is middle class why is
считаешь что такое средний класс почему
middle
вот средний
class Well what is in it What are the characteristics
класс Ну что в нём Какие характеристики
yes probably not simple How much does he
да наверное не просто Сколько он
get And what can you buy with this
получает А что можно купить на эти
money yeah Yeah Well why that's what do you
деньги да Угу Ну почему вот что как ты
think What classifies a person as middle
считаешь Что относит человека к среднему
class apartment car
классу квартира машина
education it
образование
turns out
получается
apartment education So let's do it then a
квартира образования Так давай так тогда
person in Moscow receiving 1,500
человек в Москве получающий 1500
dollars an apartment is not in the cards for him True Well yes they
долларов квартира ему не светит Правда
thought then he is no longer middle
Ну да это считали то он уже не средний
class now T in general no one there  he is
классс сейчас Т вообще там никому то он
not middle class then no well with such a
не средний класс тогда не ну с такой
mortgage rate no one can afford an apartment with a mortgage
ипотеке в ипотеку квартира никому не
now if we say almost like
светит сейчас если так говорить почти
that then you have it like that wait then it turns out that you are
так то у вас вообще так подожди то у вас
middle class it
получается средний класс это тысяч 5-6
should be 5-6 thousand dollars yes like to
долларов должно быть
afford an apartment now you mean Well look
позволить вы имеете в виду Ну смотри
middle class yes That is if you
средний класс да То есть если ты вот
say here is an apartment a car then it turns out that
скажешь вот квартира машина то
now the middle class In Russia
получается сейчас средний класс В России
it is the one who earns at least thousand dollars yes Well
это тот кто получает тысяч долларов хотя
I I just like don't understand the question in
Ну я я просто типа не понимаю вопрос в
terms of how you could
плане что бы ты квартиру себе мог
afford to buy an apartment or what do you mean in the World Cup
позволить купить или что в ЧМ чём смысле
let's look you gave a definition that the
давай так смотри ты дал определение что
middle class is a person who
средний класс - это человек который
has a stable income and can use a wide
имеет стабильные доходы и может широкий
range of intangible benefits that
спектр там нематериальных благ использ
is to buy an apartment buy a car and
то есть купить квартиру купить машину и
so on So you and I decided that
так дальше Вот мы с тобой решили по
dollars a month is not enough to buy an
долларов в месяц не хватит чтобы купить
apartment in Moscow so according to the debt it is not
квартиру в Москве значит по дол это не
middle
средний
class so middle class Let's
класс значит средний класс Давай будем
take 4-5 ssia dollars this is the middle class
брать 4-5 сся долларов это средний класс
in Russia Well okay All then who are
в России Ну хорошо Всё то кто ж такие
the rich in Russia how much should they
богачи в России сколько они должны
earn well
получать ну
twice as much if not
кратно раза в два больше если не
three times
три
that is  88,000 dollars 81,000
точно то есть 88.000 долларов 81000
dollars is already Rich man a month Yeah,
долларов это уже Богач месяц Да ну
definitely Yeah, I get it, I get it Well, that's
определённо Да
good Well, like, somewhere,
понял Ну это это хорошее Ну типа где-то
few people earn that much Well, how
мало людей столько зарабатываю Ну как
few is few, but in terms of relatives, if
мало мало но в плане относительно если
we consider that there are 140 million of us in the country, then, like, certainly,
мы считаем что нас 140 мл в стране то
few people
как бы точно немного лько людей
earn that much but
зарабатывает нуно это уже скоре ну как
that's already more likely, how is it already more likely, anyway, yes,
это уже скорее всего по-любому это да
either someone works in a narrowly focused
это либо кто-то в узко направленной
profession, a very valuable employee,
профессии работает очень ценный кадр
or that's already we're starting there, that is, do
либо это вот уже мы начинаем там то есть
I understand correctly Yeah, well, if we say
я правильно понимаю Да ээ лу если скажем
so, it's better to
так лучше
earn 5,000 dollars and there 88,000
зарабатывать 5.000 долларов и там 88.000
dollars in Russia than to be rich in
долларов в России чем быть богачом во
France
Франции
Yeah, well, I do
да ну
n't know, it's good in France, it's
не знаю во Франции
hard,
хорошо тяжёлый
of course Well, let's be
конечно Ну давай так давай всё-таки по
honest Why do people leave
чесноку Почему люди уезжают жить из
Russia to live in Europe And from Europe to Russia
России в Европу А из Европы в Россию
No, well,
Нет ну потому
because those who care about material goods,
что те кому важны материальные блага
so to speak, have less strength Yeah, like
так сказать меньше сил получаются Да ну
in America, like yes If we
как и в Америке типа да Если так
say so, like, it makes no difference Europe America,
говорить типа без разницы Европа Америка
yes,
да
for,
за
say, less, more money Yeah, let's say,
скажем за меньше больше деньги Да скажем
for the
так за
same amount of time  in essence yes
одинаковое время по сути да вложенное в
people receive different wages for their work
свой труд люди получают разную оплату
yes in essence yes Pony and in Europe it is
труда да По сути да Поня и в Европе он
higher yes It all means it is better in Europe
выше да Всё значит в Европе
Well I guess you got it And what is better in
лучше Ну наверное понял А что лучше в
Russia can you give three examples What is
России можешь сказать три примера Что
better in Russia than in Europe or in
лучше в России чем в Европе или в
America than in Europe and in
Америке чем в Европе и в
[music]
[музыка]
America well from that Well I'll say for sure well
Америке ну из такого Ну точно скажу ну
food well in any case food like
еда ну по-любому еда типа
meat we would even if we look at the price
мясо бы мы даже если по цене будем
like it's in America they have
смотреть типа он в Америке у них с
problems with eggs there now Wait Stop come on have
яйцами там сейчас проблем Подожди Стоп
you ever been to Europe no I
давай так ты в Европе был когда-то нет
understand what you think Where are the better products
понял как ты считаешь Где лучше продукты
in Russia or in
в России или в
Europe Such a controversial issue that you won't
Европе Такой типа спорный вопрос то что
know if you haven't tried it or what have you
не попробовал не узнаешь или чтом тыш
tried European products Have you
пробовал европейские продукты Ты
tried Well that's what I'm saying No it's like
пробовал Ну так я вот говорю Нет это как
you don't have European raw
нет у вас в России европейские сырые
European sausages meat like
европейские есть колбасы мясо типа
European there was jamon And so on
Европейское было там хамон И так дальше
And so there are a lot of them produced in
А так они там очень много произведены на
factories in Russia like
заводах в России как
Italian cheeses produced in factories in Russia
это итальянские сыры на заводах в России
about full import yes like full
про полный импорт да типа полностью
import Well yes yes products European
импорт Ну да да продукты европейские
products
продукты
which we just see that European products are
которые просто мы видим что европейские
sold in Russia and on the contrary
продукты в России продаются а наоборот
can you tell me which one  in Europe, a
можешь мне подсказать какой в Европе
Russian product is sold Well, if it's not like a non-
российский Ну если это не типа не
Russian store, what are they called there,
русский магазин как они там называются
right, in terms of Well, you get the idea, etc., where there are
правильно в плане Ну вы поняли проч где
only Russian goods, yes, then I think
только русские товары то да то я думаю
everything of their own is on the shelves Well, especially
всё своё на полках имеется Ну особенно
now, like, obviously, someone more than that in
сейчас типа явно кого-то больше того в
Europe, do you agree that in Europe, the
Европе ты согласен что в Европе
standards for products are GOSTs Yes, they are
стандарты по продукции ГОСТы Да они
much stricter than in Russia, but I don't
намного жёстче чем в России а это не
know who I am, I won't say, it's grown up in Russia, you
знаю кти не буду говорить врос в России
can feed people whatever you want and
можно кормить людей чем угодно и ничто
nothing will happen to you for it Well, yes,
тебе за это не
we have tricks there, that's
будет Ну да у нас там есть Уловки это
also a fact, yes, like, you can
тоже факт да типа там можно с этим
twist it with this GOST like that, yes, yes So, maybe
гостом вот покрутить его вот так вот
medicine is better in Russia, in Israel, medicine So,
медицина в Израиле медицина Так что
maybe education is better in
может образование лучше в
Russia Well, now you'll say again that people
России ну сейчас опять скажете что
go to study in America
учиться едут в Америку
Yes, maybe the ecology is better in Russia than in
Да может экология лучше в России чем в
Europe
Европе
Well, somewhere in certain places, probably,
Ну где-то в определённых местах наверно
yes, in which ones Well, you can go live in the taiga,
каких Ну он можно в тайгу жить пойти не
go and build it up, it's purely good,
Поня пойти застроить се чисто хорош
let's have three, we didn't succeed, let's
давай мы три у нас не получилось давай
try at least one element at the end of the conversation, the
так напоследок разговора попробуем хоть
criterion by which it is better to
один элемент критерий по которому лучше
live in Russia than in Europe
жить в России чем в Европе
ok I don't
хорошо не
know here you are as a resident Look Imagine
знаю вот ты как житель Смотри Представь
Yes you are a resident of the Russian Federation You are
Да ты житель Российской Федерации Ты
now at the International Olympiad to
сейчас на Международной олимпиаде по
represent your countries yes
представлению своих стран да вот
all the countries have performed in short and you need to
выступили все страны короче и тебе нужно
say Yes now What is the advantage of
сказать Да теперь В чём преимущество
living in Russia at least one
жизни в России хотя бы один
criterion Well we are good we are kind
критерий Ну у нас хорошо мы добрые Все
We are all not as evil as they say on
мы не такие злые как говорят по
TV that's how it
телевизору вот так
turns out in Russia there is no point in living there is
вот получается в России нет смысла жить
only point in
есть смысл только
Dying
Умирать
that's all like a squeak
так вот и всё лайк писка ко
on y Instagram I don't know why this is
на й Instagram Я не знаю для чого це то
for that there is looking at the office and for you
для то там дивитись на офес а для тебе
ond and three clicks and you trim me and I
онд а три клика а ты тримае мене и я
will be in me there are a bunch of fouls and in me there will be a
буду в мене там Купа фолов и в мене буде
cool naib Robi but cool video letter on
класный найб Роби но крут видео пись на
y inst pok Andriy
й inst пок Андрий
so let's go
так давайка
with
с